AskAnna Privacy Statement
=========================

Introduction
------------

This Privacy Statement sets out how your personal data is processed when using the website and/or the services of AskAnna. Please read this document carefully before making use of our website and/or our services. AskAnna is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Therefore, we strive to handle your personal data with care and in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other applicable privacy laws. The Privacy Statement applies to all AskAnna services. The terms governing your use of the AskAnna services are defined in our [Terms of Use](https://askanna.io/terms/).

If you have questions about our Privacy Statement or the way we process your personal data, you may contact us via:

> AskAnna B.V.  
> Stationsplein 45, unit A4.004  
> 3013 AK Rotterdam
> 
> [\[email protected\]](https://askanna.io/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

[Dutch Chamber of Commerce number](https://www.kvk.nl/): 75877848

Personal data collected
-----------------------

AskAnna shall only collect and process personal data that is necessary when using our website, when carrying out research, for the performance of our other services and/or data that you have provided us, unless stated otherwise in this Privacy Statement. We may process the following personal data:

* User data such as name, address, postal code, phone number, email address, etc.
* Payment and purchase data
* Other information that you provide us when contacting us (email, online contact forms, other correspondence)
* Usage data; the data that is collected about you when you are accessing and/or using the AskAnna services

We do not intend to process personal data of persons younger than 16 years old without parental permission. We also do not have the intention to process so-called special categories of personal data (such as health or medical data), therefore we ask you not to provide us any such personal data.

Purpose and legal basis
-----------------------

The data collected by AskAnna shall only be used to facilitate the use of our websites, for the performance of an agreement, and to improve the performance of our services. Under no circumstances will your personal data be provided to third parties for commercial purposes without your explicit permission.

AskAnna will process your personal data for the following reasons:

* For processing payments you make
* To inform you of the changes that have been made regarding our services
* To send out newsletters
* To carry out research
* For the performance of an agreement
* To comply with legal obligations, such as data needed for our tax return

Our processing of personal data is based on the legal grounds of your express consent or, if necessary, for the performance of an agreement or if this is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation that we are subject to. Personal data is not subjected to decision making based solely on automated processing (such as profiling).

Term
----

AskAnna will keep your personal data for no longer than necessary for the processing purposes mentioned above. This means that your personal data are kept for as long as necessary to fulfil the specified purposes. AskAnna will retain your data for a period of 4 weeks and if you request, we will delete or anonymise your personal data so that it no longer identifies you. However, we are bound to retain certain personal data for longer as AskAnna must comply with its statutory retention obligations such as the duty to retain data for tax purposes, audit and accounting obligations. In those cases only, AskAnna will retain your data for a period of 7 years.

Security
--------

AskAnna is committed to ensuring that your data is secure. In order to prevent misuse, loss, unauthorized access, unwanted disclosure, and unauthorized modification, AskAnna has suitable physical, technical, and organizational procedures to safeguard and secure the data. If you are under the impression that your data is not properly protected or if there are any indications of abuse, you can contact us by using the contact details at the top of the page.

Controlling your personal data
------------------------------

The General Data Protection Regulation or “GDPR” gives certain rights to individuals in relation to their personal data. Accordingly, we are happy to offer transparency and access controls to help users take advantage of those rights. As available and except as limited under applicable law, the rights afforded to individuals are:

* to access your personal data
* to rectification of your personal data
* to erasure your personal data
* to withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data
* to restriction of processing of your personal data
* to object processing of your personal data
* to data portability of your personal data

You may [\[email protected\]](https://askanna.io/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to exercise your privacy rights to the abovementioned contact details. In order to ensure that the request for access has been made by you, we ask you to send a copy of your identity document with the request. In this copy, the passport photo, MRZ (machine readable zone, the strip with numbers at the bottom of the passport), passport number and Citizen Service Number must be made black. This is to protect your privacy. AskAnna will respond to your request as soon as possible, but in any case within two weeks.

If you are not pleased about how we process your personal data, you may file a complaint with the competent data protection authority and seek a judicial remedy. To file a complaint, you may use the complaint form on the website of the competent data protection authority. You can obtain the information for contacting EU data protection authorities at: [https://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index\_en.htm](https://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm)

Disclosing your personal data to third parties
----------------------------------------------

AskAnna will not sell your personal data to third parties. We may disclose your personal data to third parties insofar as reasonably necessary for the services we provide, the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement or to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

Transfer of data outside the European Economic Area (EEA)
---------------------------------------------------------

AskAnna may process your personal data outside the EEA. If your personal data is processed outside the EEA, we will ensure that appropriate safeguards will be provided. For example, by providing an adequate level of protection under an agreement which covers the EU requirements for the transfer of personal data outside the EU, such as the European Commission approved standard contractual clauses.

Changes to the Privacy Statement
--------------------------------

This Privacy Statement is subject to change. Adjustments or changes in the course of time may be reason for us to further improve the Privacy Statement. Regularly check this Privacy Statement to ensure you take note of the latest version.

This Privacy Statement was last updated in December, 2020.

* ### [AskAnna - Run, track & reproduce data science](https://askanna.io/)
    
* [\[email protected\]](https://askanna.io/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) | [Journal](https://askanna.io/journal/) | [Follow us on LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/company/askanna-io/) or [Twitter](https://twitter.com/AskAnnaHQ)

* [Privacy Statement](https://askanna.io/privacy/), [Terms of Use](https://askanna.io/terms/) & [Data Processing Agreement](https://askanna.io/dpa/)
* Copyright © 2019 - present AskAnna B.V.
